Espy, Watt; Papers apap301
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1803-2001; Undated; 4; 6.5 cubic ft.
  - Guillotine, 1956 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Hanging, 1878; 1905; 1933-1948; 1978-1996 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Hawaii, non-capital, 1936 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Idaho, non-capital, 1943; 2001 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Illinois, 1986; 1990-1994 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Illinois, 1927-1957; 1973-1993 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Illinois, lynchings, 1844-1933 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Illinois, non-capital A-M, 1934-1998; Undated (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Illinois, non-capital N-W, 1936-1990 (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Images, Death Row portraits of Mark Jenkinson, Undated (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Images, execution invitations, gravestones, reward posters, historic sites, Undated (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Images, identified portraits of individuals executed likely from the walls of Espy's home, 1938-1994; Undated (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Images, identified portraits of individuals executed likely from the walls of Espy's home, Undated (Box 50 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Images, identified portraits of individuals executed- Oversized, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Images, portraits of persons not executed but who were or are on death row, 1979; 1983-1985; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Images, unidentified executions and execution equipment, 1977; 1982; 1988; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Images, unidentified images, possibly of persons executed and taken from the walls of Espy's home, Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3-5)
  - Indiana, 1937; 1988-1991; 1996 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Indiana, lynchings, 1890-1993; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Indiana, non-capital, 1930-2001 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Innocents, 1951; 1979; 1984-2001; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Iowa, 1991-1992 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Iowa, lynchings, 1857; 1875; 1984; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Iowa, non-capital, 1943-1968; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Insanity, 1941; 1947; 1972 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - International, non-capital, 1979 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Judge Isaac Parker and Fort Smith, Arkansas, 1908; 1949; 1970-1977 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Jurors, 1945; 1986; 1990; 1997 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Juveniles, 1954-1956; 1977; 1983-1999 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Kansas, 1938; 1963-1998 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Kansas, lynchings, 1902-1988 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Kansas, non-capital, 1991 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Kentucky, 1874-1900; 1935-1951; 1970; 1980-1992 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Kentucky, 1892; 1924-1954; 1989-1992; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Kentucky, lynchings, 1858-1990; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Kentucky, non-capital, 1901-2000; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Last meals, 1947; 1990; 1998 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Last words, 1944; 1992; 1995; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Law enforcement killed on duty, 1958; 1970; 1984-1986; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Lethal injection, 1979-1993; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Louisiana, 1925-1941; 1970; 1982-1983 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Louisiana, 1874-1890; 1930-1961; 1970-1989 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Louisiana, lynchings, 1811-1979; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Louisiana, non-capital, 1882-1998; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Low IQ, 1988-1989 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Lynchings, 1962; 1969 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Lynchings, 1894; 1899; 1934; 1937 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Lynchings, the crisis articles, 1910-1926 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Lynching statistics, 1912-1970; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Maine, non-capital, 1938 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Maryland, 1936-1967; 1977-1991; Undated (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Maryland, lynchings, 1880; 1934 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Maryland, non-capital, 1934; 1996 (Box 51 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Massachusetts, 1850-1854; 1934-1958; 1977-1999; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Massachusetts, Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Massachusetts, 1936-1957 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Mentally disabled, 1989; 1997; 2001; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Michigan, 1948-1978; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Michigan, non-capital, 1935-1946 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Military, 1940-1959; 1977-1996; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Military, non-capital, 1945; 1990 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Minnesota, lynchings, 1882 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Minnesota, non-capital, 1942 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Mississippi, 1928-1940; 1951; 1969-1987; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Mississippi, lynchings, 1892-1959 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Mississippi, non-capital, 1934-1985; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Missouri, 1882; 1929-1952; 1987-1998 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Missouri, lynchings, 1896-1942 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Missouri, non-capital, 1902-1998; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Montana, non-capital, 1900; 1954 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Multiple state, lynchings, 1880; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Murder, Incorporated, 1939-1945; 1951; 1994 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Murder, Incorporated, 1937; 1940-1945; 1951-1965 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Nebraska, lynchings, 1890; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Nebraska, non-capital, 1939; 1951; 1998 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Nevada, 1991; 1995; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Nevada, lynchings, 1985-1987 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Nevada, non-capital, 1955-1998 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - New Hampshire, 1955; 1974-1990; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - New Hampshire, non-capital, 1955 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - New Jersey, 1954; 1978; 1986; 1990 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - New Jersey, non-capital, 1903-1996 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - New Mexico, 1948; 1953; 1977-1991 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - New Mexico, lynchings, 1970; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - New Mexico, non-capital, 1981 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - New York, 1930-1963; 1978-1995; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - New York, non-capital, A-M, 1934-1996; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - New York, non-capital, O-W, 1937-1988 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - New York, non-capital statewide records, 1946; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - North Carolina, 1925-1945; 1964-1993; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - North Carolina, lynchings, 1921; 1986 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - North Carolina, non-capital, 1926-1970; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - North Dakota, lynchings, Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - North Dakota, non-capital, 1956 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Official Detective articles, 1934-1938; 1953 (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Ohio, 1889; 1891; 1922-1950; 1983-1995; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Ohio, 1889; 1891; 1922-1950; 1983; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Ohio, 1960-1973; 1982; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Ohio, 1961; 1973; 1991; 2000; Undated (Box 52 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Ohio, lynchings, 1895-1918 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Ohio, non-capital, B-R, 1933-1975; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Ohio, non-capital, S-W, 1934-1993 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Ohio, non-capital, statewide, 1991 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Oklahoma, lynchings, 1880-1913 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Oklahoma, non-capital, 1940-1999 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Oregon, 1935; 1952; 1970-1997 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Oregon, non-capital, 1939; 1946; 1948 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Pain during execution, 1990-1994 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Pennsylvania, 1944-1949; 1966-1968; 1984; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10-11)
  - Pennsylvania, 1891; 1942-1998; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania, non-capital, 1931-1998 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Philippines, 1989 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Physician participation, Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Prejean, Sister Helen, 1990; 1996-1997 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Prison life, 1942; 1970-1971; 1987-1998 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Psychological Perspectives, 1968; 1986; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Quality of death row defense, 1987; 1990; 1998 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Real Detective magazine articles, 1931; 1933; 1934 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Religious views, 1941; 1988-2000 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Rhode Island, 1989; 1995 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Signed pen-and-ink drawing of electric chair, 1992 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Slavery, 1896; 1921; 1939; 1966-1976; 1980 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23-24)
  - South Carolina, 1950-1962; 1982-1996 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - South Carolina, lynchings, 1857-1902; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - South Carolina, non-capital, 1935-1989; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - South Dakota, 1942; 1985 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - South Dakota, lynchings, 1885 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - South Dakota, non-capital, 1937 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Supreme court decisions, 1969; 1983-1988; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Tennessee, 1942; 1949; 1971-1992; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Tennessee, lynchings, 1878-1985 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Tennessee, non-capital, 1936-1937; 1974; 1983 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Tesla, Nikola, Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Texas, 1905; 1932-1940; 1967-1995; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Texas, 1895; 1972-1998; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Texas, 1983-1999; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Texas, lynchings, 1858-1994; Undated (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Texas, non-capital, 1879-2001 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Thomas Albert petition, 1985 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Torture, 1986; 1998 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Trading cards, opened and unopened, 1992 (Artifact-box 1)
  - True Detective series by Luke S. May, 1932-1940 (Box 53 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - True Detective articles, 1931; 1933; 1934; 1946 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Utah, 1992 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Utah, lynchings, 1863 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Utah, non-capital, 1945 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Van Raalte Project, 1985 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Virginia, 1962; 1985; 1998 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6-7)
  - Virginia, 1965; 1985-1992 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Virginia, lynchings, 1936; Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Virginia, non-capital, 1935-2001; Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Wardens office notices and death penalty procedures, 1963-1964 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Washington, 1952; 1960; 1980-1989; Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Washington, lynchings, 1891-1975 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Washington, non-capital, 1936-1960 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - West Virginia, 1932; 1994; Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - West Virginia, lynchings, 1957; Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Williams, Wayne, Undated (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Wisconsin, 1958; 1989; 1995 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Wisconsin, non-capital, 1932; 1940; 1957 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Women, 1930-1967; 1984-1996 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Wyoming, 1932; 1966 (Box 54 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
- Correspondence, 1962-2007; Undated; 5; 7.5 cubic ft.; 7.5 cu. ft.
  Watt Espy sent and received a significant amount of correspondence as part of his work on the Capital Punishment Research Project. The majority of correspondence, however, was not organized when it arrived at the University at Albany. The archivists elected to arrange it into two groups: files devoted to prominent or regular correspondents, and general correspondence. The former includes key academics (Michael Radelet, Hugo Bedeau, Margaret Vandiver), attorneys (The California Appellate Project, NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Ohio Public Defender's Office), death penalty abolitionists and advocacy group executives (Rev. Joe Ingle, Sister Helen Prejean, Henry Schwarzschild), prominent prisoners and their families (Kerry Max Cook, Gary McGivern), and researchers who frequently corresponded with Espy. There were also a small number of files that Espy organized by subject, such as letters to and from prisoners, telephone inquiries, or correspondence relating to executions in a particular state, and the archivists retained this order and kept the files in the first group. The second group includes more infrequent correspondents, usually general inquiries sent to libraries or archives for records relating to individuals executed or for research requests.
  Please see Series 3: Capital Punishment Research Project for correspondence specifically relating to Espy's work at the University of Alabama School of Law and the National Science Foundation grant and Series 6: Biographical Materials for correspondence related to some of Espy's publications, testimony, speaking events, and signed portrait and autograph collection.
  - Abbott, Jack, 1981 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Agresti, David, University of South Florida, 1981; 1984-1987 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Agresti, David, University of South Florida, 1988 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Agresti, David, University of South Florida, 1988; 1996 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Allen, Howard, Southern Illinois University at Carbondale, 1995-1996 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Alabama closed, 1974-1980; 1982-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Alabama Coalition Against the Death Penalty, 1983-1984; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Alabama legislature, 1981 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Alabama outstanding, 1976-1979; 1981-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Alabama Peace Officers' Association, 1981 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Alabama Prison Project, 1980; 1982-1987; 1989; 1997; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Alaska, 1977; 1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Amnesty International, Austrian Section, 1985 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Amnesty International USA, 1988-1989; 1991; 1993 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Andrews, George, Congress of the United States, 1962; 1964; 1968-1969 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - The Angolite, Louisiana State Prison, William Rideaux and Ronald Wikberg, 1987-1992; 1995; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Arizona closed, 1974; 1977; 1979; 1981-1984 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Arizona open, 1977; 1980-1982; 1984 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Arkansas closed, 1974-1977; 1979; 1981-1984; 1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Arkansas outstanding, 1976-1978; 1981-1982; 1985 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - The Atlanta Constitution, Tom Teppen, Bill Shipp, 1985-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Bailey, William C., Cleveland State University, 1984; 1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Barnard, William, University of Alabama, 1982; 1984 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Beatty, Sam, Justice- Supreme Court of Alabama, 1985-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Bedau, Hugo, 1980-1983 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Bedau, Hugo, 1984-1989 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Bedau, Hugo, Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Bevill, Tom, Congress of the United States, House of Representatives, 1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Bexar County, Texas, District clerk, 1978-1980 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Biffle, Kent, Dallas Morning News, 1995-1996 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Blackwelder, Robert E., Wallace Community College, 1984-1985; 1988; 1992 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Blaine, Quentin, 1987 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Bowers, William, Northeastern University, 1984-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Bray, Bendard, Talladega College, 1983; 1989; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Buffalo and Erie County Public Library, 1978-1979 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Bushwhacker Museum, Vernon County (MS) Historical Society, 1977 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - California Appellate Project, Allen Hopper, Michael Millman, Lisa Short, 1983-1989; 1991; 2001 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - California closed, 1974-1977; 1979-1983; 1985-1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - California outstanding, 1976-1978; 1981-1984 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Callahan, Harriet, Louisiana State Library, 1986 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Callahan, Marguerite, 1975-1977; 1979-1980; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Capital Collateral Representative, Ken Driggs, Michael Mello Larry Helm Spalding, Terry Farley Walsh, 1985; 1990-1992 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Capital Collateral Representative, Ken Driggs, Larry Helm Spalding, Terry Farley Walsh, 1992-1993 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Christianson, Scott, 1982; 1983; 1985 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Chattanooga Public Library, 1974-1975 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Clemency Requests and Related Correspondence, 1979-1980; 1983-1988; 1994; Undated (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Committee Against Executions, Valda Winsloe Restrepo, 1981 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Commonwealth of Kentucky, Department of Public Advocacy, 1986; 1989 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Conyers, John, Congress of the United States, House of Representatives, 1985-1987 (Box 55 (5-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Cook, Kerry Max, 1988-1989 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - The Courier- Journal/ The Louisville Times, 1987 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - CURE, Charles Sullivan, 1985-1986; 1989; 1995; 1999; 2002 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Dallas Public Library, 1982 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Death Penalty Information Center, 1993; 2000 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Dent, Rick, 1983; 1985; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Denton, Jeremiah, Congress of the United States, Senate, 1985-1986 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Dickson, William, Congress of the United States, House of Representatives, 1976; 1979 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Dicks, Shirley, 1985; 1989; 2001; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Erdahl, Bishop Lowell, 1985-1986 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Eastern Shore Public Library, 1976-1977; 1979; 1983 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Equal Justice Initiative of Alabama, 1995; 1998 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Fairchild, Halford, University of California, 1986 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Fayette County (TN)Historian, 1977; 1979 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Feingold, Russell, Congress of the United States, Senate, 2001 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Flippo, Ronnie, Congress of the United States, House of Representatives, 1986; 1989 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Foster, Burk, The University of Southwestern Louisiana, 1990 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Foster, Burk, The University of Southwestern Louisiana, 1996; 1999-2000 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Frazier, Harriet, Central Missouri State University, 1985-1988 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Frazier, Harriet, Central Missouri State University, 1989-1990 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Frazier, Harriet, Central Missouri State University, 1991-1994; 2001; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Gautier, Benard, 1984 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Geimer, William, Washington and Lee University, 1985-1990; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Gillespie, Kay, 1985-1986 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Glasscock, John, 1985-1987 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Glasspole, Florizel, Governor-General of Jamaica, 1986 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Gonzales County Historical Commission, 1977; 1980 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Gorman, Jerome, 1985-1988; 1991 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Gorman, Jerome and Donna, 1984-1986; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Gorman, Jerome and Donna, 1987-1988; Undated (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University, 1988; 1995 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University, 1997 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 32-34)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University, 1998 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University (1 of 2), 1999 (Box 56 (5-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University (2 of 2), 1999 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Halperin, Rick, Amnesty International, Southern Methodist University, 2000 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Hayes, Roger Dale, 1988 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Hayes, Roger Dale, 1988; 1992 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Hearn, Daniel, 1987-1990 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Hearn, Daniel, 1990-1992; 1995-1998 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Hearn, Daniel, 1999-2002; 2005; Undated (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Heflin, Howell, Congress of the United States, Senate, 1989 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Herron, Roy Brasfield, 1985 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Hines, Liz, Louisiana State University, 1988-1989 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Holt, Wythe, 1982-1983; 1985; Undated (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Howe, Scott, University of Texas at Austin, 1988 (Box 57 (5-Correspondence), Folder 12)